<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="198" moduleid="8461" modulename="book" contextid="35842">
  <book id="198">
    <name>Introduction</name>
    <intro></intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <numbering>1</numbering>
    <navstyle>1</navstyle>
    <customtitles>0</customtitles>
    <timecreated>1550863059</timecreated>
    <timemodified>1550863059</timemodified>
    <chapters>
      <chapter id="1326">
        <pagenum>1</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Welcome to this LINCS Course</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the &lt;i&gt;Learning
Disabilities and Accommodations&lt;/i&gt; course, a research-based training on
serving adults with learning disabilities (LD). This program is brought to you
by Literacy Information and Communication System (LINCS).&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;This course was updated and funded in whole with Federal
funds from the U.S. Department of Education under the LINCS Resource Collection
contract number ED-ESE-15-A-0012/0003 with Manhattan Strategy Group. Monique
Faulkner served as the contracting officer’s representative. This course was
originally developed with federal funds from the National Institutes for
Literacy. The content of this course does not necessarily reflect the views or
policies of the U.S. Department of Education nor does the mention of trade
names, commercial products, or organizations imply endorsement by the U.S.
Government.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1551207514</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1327">
        <pagenum>2</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Join the LINCS Community and participate in discussions</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This course is designed for teachers of adult learners
with LD. As with all LINCS courses, this course includes opportunities to
connect with other adult education practitioners interested in providing
appropriate accommodations for adult learners with learning disabilities (LD).
If you haven’t already done so, take a moment to register as a member of the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://community.lincs.ed.gov/" target="_blank"&gt;LINCS
Community&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and participate in the discussions
embedded throughout this course. The discussions provide an open forum to share
your thoughts, ideas, and questions with other adult education practitioners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout this course, you will have the opportunity to
share your stories and insights as you learn about the various accommodations
appropriate for adult learners with LD. This is a great opportunity to share
and learn from others. We encourage you to participate!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1550863215</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1328">
        <pagenum>3</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Overview and objectives</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this course, we will describe and explore accommodations
that instructors of adult learners with learning disabilities may provide their
students to ensure equal access to educational services and resources. Let's
start by reviewing the learning goals of this lesson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="_Hlk528755193"&gt;Upon completion of this course,
you will be able to:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;!--[endif]--&gt;define accommodations;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;identify different types of accommodations;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;describe how to access accommodations, and:&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;understand the importance of Universal Design.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;!--[if !supportLists]--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;









&lt;p&gt;Please allow approximately 1 hour to complete this course.
However, you are free to leave the session at any time. When you exit the
courseware, a bookmark is automatically placed at your last location to allow
you to pick up where you left off when you return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span&gt;Navigation &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course is divided up into several sections:
understanding accommodations; accessing accommodations through
self-determination, self-disclosure, and self-advocacy; and universal design. Navigate
through the course by using the forward arrows available on each page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1551207555</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1329">
        <pagenum>4</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Scenario-based instruction</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Throughout this course, you will be presented with scenarios
of individuals who may need accommodations to perform better in a given
learning environment. These scenarios are designed to help you understand how
accommodations work in real life situations. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you read each scenario, review the questions that
follow and select the best response. But before we explore the scenarios, we
will first define and describe the term &lt;b&gt;accommodations&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1550863712</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
    </chapters>
    <chaptertags>
    </chaptertags>
  </book>
</activity>