<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="203" moduleid="8466" modulename="book" contextid="35847">
  <book id="203">
    <name>Setting Accommodations</name>
    <intro></intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <numbering>1</numbering>
    <navstyle>1</navstyle>
    <customtitles>0</customtitles>
    <timecreated>1551114371</timecreated>
    <timemodified>1551114371</timemodified>
    <chapters>
      <chapter id="1357">
        <pagenum>1</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Categories of setting accommodations</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The fourth accommodation we will discuss is setting. Setting
accommodations refer to changes to the location in which a student receives
instruction or takes a test. Setting accommodations may also mean modifying the
conditions of an instructional or testing setting.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting accommodations benefit students who are easily
distracted or who concentrate best in small group or individual settings. A
setting accommodation may reduce distractions by allowing a student to do
individual work in a different location, usually in a place with few or no
other students. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are
four general categories of setting accommodations that allow the student to
focus better on classroom tasks and tests:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Moving the student to a different seat within in
the classroom;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Moving the student to a private room &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Moving the student to a quiet room, or &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Allowing the student to participate in a small
group setting. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;!--[if !supportLists]--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;







&lt;p&gt;Students
who might perform better when they can read aloud or make noises that distract
other students may benefit from the occasional use of individual learning
settings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1551244264</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1358">
        <pagenum>2</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Examples of setting accommodations</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Consider Derek,
an adult learner who can be easily distracted in a classroom environment if he
is sitting near doors, windows, etc. Derek finds it easier to concentrate if he
is sitting in a physically enclosed space with little visual stimuli. He
operates most effectively if no other individuals are present in the room. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/Pic_man%20studying%202.jpg" alt="A young man struggles to study because of auditory distractions." width="2449" height="1632" style="max-width:100%; height:auto;" class="img-responsive atto_image_button_text-bottom"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Photo Copyright: Andriy Popov, licensed through 123rf subscription service&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1551297814</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
    </chapters>
    <chaptertags>
    </chaptertags>
  </book>
</activity>