<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="199" moduleid="8462" modulename="book" contextid="35843">
  <book id="199">
    <name>Understanding Accommodations</name>
    <intro></intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <numbering>1</numbering>
    <navstyle>1</navstyle>
    <customtitles>0</customtitles>
    <timecreated>1550863971</timecreated>
    <timemodified>1550863971</timemodified>
    <chapters>
      <chapter id="1330">
        <pagenum>1</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Accommodations help ensure fair, equitable access to educational services</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Accommodations adjust the manner in which instructional,
testing, and employment situations are presented or evaluated without changing
the actual standards a student is working toward, so that an individual with
learning disabilities can demonstrate his or her knowledge in a fair and
equitable fashion. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accommodations individualize instruction to meet diverse
learning levels and are legally mandated. These instructions may include combining
oral instruction with visual handouts or reading aloud material that is too
difficult for a learner. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this topic, you will learn the four types of
accommodations and the features of effective accommodations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1550864001</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1331">
        <pagenum>2</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Four types of accommodations</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;There are four main types of accommodations that may be utilized by a company or facility, or in an educational setting.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Presentation &lt;/b&gt;–&amp;nbsp; A change to the way information is presented.&lt;br&gt;Example: A student listens to an audio version of book instead of reading the text.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Response&lt;/b&gt; – A change in the way assignments or tests are completed.&lt;br&gt;Example: A student is given an oral exam instead of a written exam.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Scheduling or Timing&lt;/b&gt; – A change in the amount of time a student is given to complete tasks or a change to the number or timing of breaks the student is given.&lt;br&gt;Example: Allow students fifty percent more time to complete the task (e.g. provide 15 minutes for a 10 minute task.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Setting&lt;/b&gt;– A change in the environment.&lt;br&gt;Example: A student is allowed to take a test in a separate room away from other students and potential distractions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Later in this course, we will discuss the different types of accommodations in detail.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1555956169</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1332">
        <pagenum>7</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Features of accommodations</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Accommodations have four key features.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;First, accommodations are &lt;b&gt;individualized&lt;/b&gt; to emphasize a person's strengths and work around
their weaknesses, as well as the demands of the situation.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Second, accommodations require &lt;b&gt;documentation from a licensed clinician&lt;/b&gt;
who is trained to administer diagnostic testing for learning disabilities. This
documentation will help determine the needs of the individual and the most
appropriate type of accommodation. However, if documentation is unavailable,
the instructor should use his or her best judgment to assist the student in
class.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Third, accommodations &lt;b&gt;do not interfere with the skill or concept being taught&lt;/b&gt;. For
instance, if reading decoding is the skill being measured on a test, a person
reading the test to the student might not be an acceptable accommodation.
However, if science knowledge is the skill being measured on the test, a person
reading the test to a student so they can answer the questions might be a
reasonable accommodation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fourth, accommodations for documented learning
disabilities &lt;b&gt;provide access to a
learning environment to which all Americans are entitled&lt;/b&gt;. The Legal Right
of Access for students with disabilities is derived from several federal laws,
including the 14th Amendment, Title VI of the Civil Rights Act, the Equal
Opportunity Act of 1974, and the Americans with Disabilities Act.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;More Information&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;More information about accommodations
is available on the &lt;span style="background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255);"&gt;&lt;a href="https://nceo.info/" target="_blank"&gt;National
Center for Education Outcomes (NCEO)&lt;/a&gt; website&lt;/span&gt;. NCEO, housed at the
University of Minnesota, provides leadership on evidence-based information on
inclusive assessments and comprehensive assessment systems. NCEO aims to
benefit students with disabilities, English learners, and English learners with
disabilities through their efforts to support the implementation of U.S.
Department of Education accountability systems. &lt;span style="background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255);"&gt;&lt;a href="https://nceo.info/Resources/publications/onlinepubs" target="_blank"&gt;NCEO publications&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
are freely available online, including a comprehensive &lt;span style="background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255);"&gt;&lt;a href="https://nceo.info/Resources/publications/OnlinePubs/AccommBibliography/AccomStudMethods.htm" target="_blank"&gt;bibliography
of accommodations studies.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1565807747</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1333">
        <pagenum>3</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Does Hamid need accommodations?</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our first scenario is about Hamid, a young immigrant. Read
Hamid’s story, then determine whether he needs accommodations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span&gt;Hamid’s Story&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hamid is taking adult basic education classes to improve his reading skills so he can complete his General Education Development test, regularly referred to as the GED. Hamid emigrated from Iran&lt;br&gt;when he was five years old. He was diagnosed with a Learning Disability (LD) when in the public schools. Unfortunately, he has no past evaluation documentation from his high school years to provide support for accessing&lt;br&gt;accommodations on the GED.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/hamid%20%282%29.png" alt="A young man of middle-eastern descent" width="147" height="190" class="img-responsive atto_image_button_right"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h5&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;Based on the information provided, does Hamid need accommodations?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol type="a"&gt;&lt;li&gt;Yes&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;No&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you have decided on your answer, advance to the next page for the correct answer and the next question.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1551293734</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1334">
        <pagenum>4</pagenum>
        <subchapter>1</subchapter>
        <title>Qualification</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;Based on Hamid’s earlier diagnosis of a learning disability, he does qualify for accommodations.&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/hamid%20%282%29.png?time=1550871804487" alt="a young man of middle-eastern descent" width="147" height="190" class="img-responsive atto_image_button_right"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h5&gt;Hamid’s Story&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hamid is taking adult basic education classes to improve his reading skills so he can complete his General Education Development test, regularly referred to as the GED. Hamid emigrated from Iran when he was five years old. He was diagnosed with a Learning Disability (LD) when in the public schools. Unfortunately, he has no past evaluation documentation from his high school years to provide support for accessing accommodations on the GED.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h5&gt;&lt;b&gt;On what basis would Hamid’s ABE teacher provide classroom accommodations?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol type="a"&gt;&lt;li&gt;Clinician assessment&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Documentation post-high school&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;His / her best judgement&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;None of the above&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you have decided on your answer, advance to the next slide&amp;nbsp;for the correct answer and the next question.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1551293960</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1335">
        <pagenum>5</pagenum>
        <subchapter>1</subchapter>
        <title>Basis for accommodation</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hamid has no past evaluation documentation for his
learning disability; therefore, the &lt;b&gt;adult
basic education teacher&lt;/b&gt; must use his or her best judgment when determining
if Hamid requires&amp;nbsp; accommodations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h5&gt;Hamid's Story&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/hamid%20%282%29.png" alt="A young man of middle-eastern descent" width="147" height="190" class="img-responsive atto_image_button_right"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hamid is taking adult basic education
classes to improve his reading skills so he can complete his General Education
Development test, regularly referred to as the GED. Hamid emigrated from Iran
when he was five years old. He was diagnosed with a Learning Disability (LD)
when in the public schools. Unfortunately, he has no past evaluation
documentation from his high school years to provide support for accessing
accommodations on the GED.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;What accommodations would you select for Hamid?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol type="a"&gt;&lt;li&gt;Extra time for instructional and testing
situations&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;A quiet room during testing&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Enlarged font size of textbooks&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;All of the above&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;!--[if !supportLists]--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;







&lt;p&gt;Think about your answer, then advance to the next slide.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1551289717</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1336">
        <pagenum>6</pagenum>
        <subchapter>1</subchapter>
        <title>Potential accommodations</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The correct answer is d, all of the above. Hamid’s
participation in classes to improve his reading skills as well as his learning
disability suggests that he would benefit from:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;extra time for instructional and testing
situations;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;a quiet room during testing; and &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;enlarged font size of textbooks for ease of
reading.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;!--[if !supportLists]--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;





&lt;p&gt;The majority of adolescents and adults with learning
disabilities demonstrate difficulties with the speed of processing literacy
tasks (Gregg, 2009). Therefore, recognizing that Hamid has a long history of
LD, the ABE teacher might consider providing him extra time on instructional
and testing tasks. However, if Hamid requests the accommodation of extra time
on a high stakes test such as the GED, he must provide current psychological
documentation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1550871877</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
    </chapters>
    <chaptertags>
    </chaptertags>
  </book>
</activity>