<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="205" moduleid="8468" modulename="book" contextid="35849">
  <book id="205">
    <name>Universal Design</name>
    <intro></intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <numbering>1</numbering>
    <navstyle>1</navstyle>
    <customtitles>0</customtitles>
    <timecreated>1551117276</timecreated>
    <timemodified>1551117276</timemodified>
    <chapters>
      <chapter id="1367">
        <pagenum>1</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Universal design is a proactive approach to accommodations</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;Many individuals in the field of adult education suggest that we develop learning, testing, and work environments so that any person, with or without disabilities, could access accommodations. To assist facilities and companies making these accommodations, Universal Design offers a proactive approach.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this topic, you will learn:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;what universal design is;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;how universal design helps individuals with LD;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;types of universal design accommodations; and&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;resources for universal design.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Universal Design concept offers accessible design
features and minimizes the need for individually or retrofitted accommodations.
This means that accommodations can be built into programs and facilities to make
them more accessible.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Universal design for learning is an approach to curriculum
design that can help teachers customize curriculum to serve all learners,
regardless of ability, disability, age, gender, or cultural and linguistic
background. Universal design for learning is a set of principles for designing
curriculum that provides all individuals with opportunities to learn. Explore
this &lt;a href="https://lincs.ed.gov/sites/default/files/2_TEAL_UDL.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;fact sheet&lt;/a&gt;
for more information about universal design for learning. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1565809111</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1368">
        <pagenum>2</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Universal design makes alternative media more accessible to everyone</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some examples of the universal design concept already common
in our everyday lives include closed-captioning options on the television. This
serves individuals who are hearing impaired, as well as many other users who
enjoy or benefit from that option. Another example is municipalities creating curb-cuts
for individuals in wheelchairs. These also benefit individuals with strollers
or other wheeled carts, individuals who have difficulty with stairs, etc. These
universal design changes were originally meant to accommodate those with
disabilities, but resulted in a &amp;nbsp;much
wider scope by assisting all people who have access to or use these services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of universal design is to provide the best
environment for equal access to resources. With a universal design approach,
alternative media would be more accessible to the entire population without
calling specific attention to those with learning disabilities. Universal design
is about ease of use for all individuals. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the more widely heralded technologies include
e-Text for books, magazines, and newspapers; as well as mobile phone devices as
a means to scan text or download e-Text to laptops for work or school. e-Text
is fast becoming the medium of choice for a large percentage of the general
population-with or without print reading disabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons for the increasing popularity of e-Text
among adolescents and adults with learning disabilities is its portability.
Digital files can be quickly downloaded and used in a variety of environments
including mobile phones and tablets. For adolescents or adults with LD, mobile
technologies offer a quick and comprehensive tool for managing the day-to-day
reading and writing tasks both at school and work.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1551117441</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1369">
        <pagenum>3</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Training is essential to successfully accessing new technologies</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Training individuals with LD on how to access and use the
new and emerging technologies is key to making accommodations more commonplace.
Instruction is needed to teach students when using an accommodation is
essential to a positive outcome. For example, training in active listening, how
to use assistive technologies, and extended time allowances to gain proficiency
are important activities to teach those with LD how to best structure, manage,
and organize time. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="max-width:100%; height:auto;" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/Pic_man%20in%20computer%20lab%202.jpg" alt="A young man smiles at the camera in a computer lab with two other female students" width="2449" height="1632" class="img-responsive atto_image_button_text-bottom"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;Photo Copyright: ammentorp, as licensed through 123rf&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1551244435</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1370">
        <pagenum>4</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Universal design shows promise for those with LD</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Understanding that learning is fluid and dynamic is key to
ensuring ongoing education, particularly for individuals with LD. For most of
us, it begins with reading. Those with LD often become discouraged and do not
even contemplate postsecondary educational opportunities. In the world of work,
many of these individuals are underemployed or lose their jobs when reading becomes
essential to their employment. The profound changes in the digital world show
encouraging signs that more and more people with LD will benefit from tools
that incorporate universal design and ensure ease of use for all users. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Further Resources to Explore&lt;/h4&gt;

The
&lt;a href="https://askjan.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Job Accomodation Network&lt;/a&gt;
(JAN) provides free resources and guidance on workplace accommodations and
disability employment issues. JAN is funded by the U.S. Department of Labor
Office of Disability Employment Policy (ODEP).&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1565809130</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1371">
        <pagenum>5</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Resources for universal design</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="_Hlk527050297"&gt;The goal of Universal Design is to
provide the best environment for equal access to resources.&lt;/a&gt; There are
several helpful organizations that have developed resources, tools, and
initiatives to support universal design. These include: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The&lt;a href="http://www.cast.org/" target="_blank"&gt; Center for Applied Special Technology&lt;/a&gt;, CAST, is a
nonprofit research and development organization that works to expand learning
opportunities for individuals through Universal Design for Learning.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The
&lt;a href="https://www.washington.edu/doit/programs/accesscollege/faculty-room/overview" target="_blank"&gt;University of Washington's Faculty Room&lt;/a&gt; is a space for faculty and
administrators at postsecondary institutions to learn about how to create
classroom environments and academic activities that maximize the learning of
all students, including those with disabilities.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;In the corporate environment, businesses like
Microsoft and Apple integrate universal design accessibility features into
their applications. These options include a wide arrange of alternative access,
including basic voice recognition, word prediction, and abbreviation software.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Other universal design accommodations are
available through&lt;a href="http://www.Bookshare.org" target="_blank"&gt;
bookshare.org&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://books.google.com/googlebooks/library/index.html" target="_blank"&gt;Google's book
share project&lt;/a&gt;. Both of these resources partner with public libraries
to digitize and categorize public domain materials as well as digitally scan
library books for greater access.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;In addition, the &lt;a href="http://www.atpc.net/" target="_blank"&gt;Alternate Text Production Center &lt;/a&gt;serves
the alternate media needs of community colleges in California. From existing
print or electronic documents, the ATPC creates alternate media products for
use by California Community College students with print-related
disabilities.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;!--[if !supportLists]--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;







&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1565809178</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
    </chapters>
    <chaptertags>
    </chaptertags>
  </book>
</activity>