<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="204" moduleid="8467" modulename="book" contextid="35848">
  <book id="204">
    <name>Accessing Accommodations</name>
    <intro></intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <numbering>1</numbering>
    <navstyle>1</navstyle>
    <customtitles>0</customtitles>
    <timecreated>1551116301</timecreated>
    <timemodified>1551116301</timemodified>
    <chapters>
      <chapter id="1359">
        <pagenum>1</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Three steps to accessing accommodations</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Adult students can play a significant role in choosing and
accessing accommodations. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this topic, we will:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;explain the difference between instructional
accommodation and testing accommodation, and&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;describe the three essential steps each
individual must take to gain access to accommodations:&lt;/li&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;self-determination;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;self-disclosure,
and&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;self-advocacy.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;!--[if !supportLists]--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;







&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1551244306</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1360">
        <pagenum>2</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>What is the difference between instructional and testing accommodations?</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;It is important to understand the distinction between instructional accommodation and testing accommodation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Instructional accommodations&lt;/b&gt; are accommodations made in the classroom based on the student's abilities, the student's results, and the instructor's assessment of the student’s situation, and the instructor’s best judgment.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Testing accommodations &lt;/b&gt;refer to accommodations made for high-stakes tests such as the GED or college placement tests. These accommodations have restrictions and require more specific documentation before they can be implemented.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="max-width:100%; height:auto;" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/Pic_man%20testing%202.jpg" alt=" A young man having difficulty taking a test. A woman is also taking a test in the background. " width="2449" height="1632" class="img-responsive atto_image_button_text-bottom"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1551244326</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1361">
        <pagenum>3</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Self-determination requires learners to be proactive and persistent</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first step to accessing accommodations is
self-determination. This means that an individual has a productive yet
realistic understanding of his or her strengths and weaknesses, and can choose
a path in life that is satisfying and leads to success.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The learner also recognizes that he or she may need some
assistance in performing certain tasks. It is important to be able to ask for
help and recognize when accommodations are needed. The concept of
self-determination applies to us all, whether we have a disability or not.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Self-determination requires the learner to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;plan for the future by setting goals and the
steps required to achieve those goals;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;be proactive by gaining support and taking
advantage of resources to ensure success; and&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;reflect by evaluating differences between
expected outcome, performance, and actual outcome, and then adjusting for next
time.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;!--[if !supportLists]--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1551116587</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1362">
        <pagenum>4</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Questions to gain self-awareness</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Self-determination requires learners to gain self-awareness
as well as learn to value his or her self. Instructors may want to assist
students with LD in gaining self-awareness by encouraging them to consider,
discuss, or write their responses to these questions: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;What are my areas of strength? &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;What is difficult for me? &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;What do I enjoy? &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;What is important to me? &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;How well do I understand my learning disability?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;How can I explain my learning disability?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;!--[if !supportLists]--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;p&gt;Knowing the answers to these questions helps individuals
learn to value themselves by accepting one's strengths and weakness, and then
take responsibility for both successes and failures. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1551116644</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1363">
        <pagenum>5</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Self-disclosure necessary for adults with LD</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next step to accessing accommodations is
self-disclosure. This is an important next step of self-determination. It is
particularly important for individuals with LD.&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The act of self-disclosure usually means three things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;accepting the disability, &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;obtaining documentation, and &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;revealing the disability to others.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;!--[if !supportLists]--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;





&lt;p&gt;Self-disclosure could prevent a learning disability from
being misinterpreted as a lack of competence; however, the decision to
self-disclose should be made by each individual in light of his or her
circumstances.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Self-disclosure is necessary for an adult with LD in an ABE
program because, in order to receive formal or testing accommodations, one must
share personal information about his or her disability.&amp;nbsp; Adults must decide where, when, what, and how
to disclose.&amp;nbsp; They must also must provide
documentation that includes how the disability affects performance, as well as
a list of reasonable accommodations.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a postsecondary setting, adults with LD should disclose
their disability during the enrollment period to the disability services office
that oversees accommodation requests. The school’s administration office can
identify this office for learners and instructors. Review the &lt;a href="https://ldaamerica.org/rights-and-responsibilities-of-college-students-with-learning-disabilities-ld/" target="_blank"&gt;rights
and responsibilities of college students with learning disabilities&lt;/a&gt;
for more information about disclosure in a postsecondary setting. Adult
education programs in postsecondary and other settings may consider similar
processes for encouraging learners to disclose disabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, adult learners may disclose their LD to
individual instructors in order to ensure they receive the appropriate
instructional or testing accommodations within the classroom. Teachers have the
responsibility to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Allow students to disclose their disabilities in
an appropriate and confidential setting.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Acknowledge the rights of students with dignity
and respect.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Maintain the integrity of academic standards.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Maintain student confidentiality.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Provide reasonable instructional and/or testing
accommodations.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;!--[if !supportLists]--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;







&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1565809080</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1364">
        <pagenum>6</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Advantages of self-disclosure</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The advantages of self-disclosure are:&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;accommodations, &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;support network, &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;improved self-advocacy, and &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;legal protection against discrimination.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;!--[if !supportLists]--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;







&lt;p&gt;Despite these advantages, some adults choose not to
self-disclose. Their reasons can vary from fear of a sense of exclusion, sense
of weakness, or high evaluation costs to receive an official diagnosis.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1551116758</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1365">
        <pagenum>7</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Self-advocacy necessary for adults with LD</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The final step to accessing accommodations is self-advocacy.
The ability to self-advocate goes beyond self-disclosure. Self-advocacy
includes the individual's ability to understand the types of accommodations he
or she needs, as well as the ability to convey to teachers, testing entities,
and/or employers that specific accommodations are required. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, someone who has a documented learning
disability may require audio assistance when taking an exam. This person should
first inquire about his or her options in the classroom. If no in-class
accommodations, such as headphones, are available then setting accommodations
may be necessary, such as a change to another room for read-aloud options.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1551116808</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1366">
        <pagenum>8</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Importance of accessing accommodations</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;Let's take a look at a case study to understand the importance of accommodations for adult learners.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Layla&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;img style="max-width:100%; height:auto; float: right;" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/hijab.jpg?time=1551117162777" alt="A woman in a hijab" width="400" height="557" class="img-responsive atto_image_button_right"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Layla was diagnosed with LD in ninth grade and received special education services&amp;nbsp; throughout her secondary schooling. She is a very talented artist who struggles in the ability to read and write. Unfortunately, she was never able to pass her high school graduation tests to receive a diploma.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After working with a graphic artist for a few years, several opportunities for advancing her job were suggested by her employer. However, any advancement is dependent upon her ability to complete her GED and attend postsecondary schooling that leads to specialized credentials.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In relation to self-awareness, Layla is very aware of her academic strengths and weaknesses. However, she demonstrates difficulties in explaining how her abilities could be accommodated such that postsecondary schooling would be possible for her. New advances in technology, such as text-to-speech and speech-to-text software might provide her with the tools for success.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Layla has been able to disclose her reading and writing problems with her employer, and she has received positive feedback. Therefore, her ability to disclose her disabilities with service providers working to help her access accommodations in postsecondary education classes will seem more familiar to her. These service providers might also help her better understand her LD as she reviews with them her past and current psychological documentation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1551244778</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
    </chapters>
    <chaptertags>
    </chaptertags>
  </book>
</activity>